[
  {
    "id": 4901,
    "question": "aprovecho",
    "questionDetails": "Aprovecho la ocasión para dar …",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "I should like to take the opportunity here to give …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4902,
    "question": "fingir",
    "questionDetails": "Desde que salí del armario, ya no tengo que fingir.",
    "answer": "pretend",
    "answerDetails": "Since I came out of the closet, I don’t have to pretend anymore."
  },
  {
    "id": 4903,
    "question": "localizar",
    "questionDetails": "Los detectives están tratando de localizar el automóvil del sospechoso.",
    "answer": "trace",
    "answerDetails": "Detectives are trying to trace the car of the suspect."
  },
  {
    "id": 4904,
    "question": "dormí",
    "answer": "Slept"
  },
  {
    "id": 4905,
    "question": "mantenga",
    "questionDetails": "Dile que mantenga la línea abierta.",
    "answer": "keep, maintain, hold",
    "answerDetails": "Tell him to keep the line open."
  },
  {
    "id": 4906,
    "question": "tocas",
    "questionDetails": "Quisiera que me tocas es por todas partes.",
    "answer": "touch",
    "answerDetails": "I want you to touch me all over."
  },
  {
    "id": 4907,
    "question": "duela",
    "answer": "stave"
  },
  {
    "id": 4908,
    "question": "permanecer",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que es mejor permanecer cerca de la carretera.",
    "answer": "stay",
    "answerDetails": "I think it is better to stay close and road."
  },
  {
    "id": 4909,
    "question": "cállense",
    "questionDetails": "Cállense los dos y sigan buscando.",
    "answer": "shut up",
    "answerDetails": "Both of you shut up and keep looking."
  },
  {
    "id": 4910,
    "question": "simpático",
    "questionDetails": "Habló en un tono simpático.",
    "answer": "sympathetic, likeable, endearing",
    "answerDetails": "He spoke in a sympathetic tone."
  },
  {
    "id": 4911,
    "question": "hacéis",
    "questionDetails": "Sabéis lo que hacéis.",
    "answer": "do",
    "answerDetails": "You know what you do."
  },
  {
    "id": 4912,
    "question": "profundamente",
    "questionDetails": "Encendió un cigarrillo e inhaló profundamente.",
    "answer": "deeply, profoundly, soundly",
    "answerDetails": "She lit a cigarette and inhaled deeply."
  },
  {
    "id": 4913,
    "question": "perseguir",
    "questionDetails": "Perseguir ese sentimiento inicial que nunca lo recupera ras.",
    "answer": "pursue",
    "answerDetails": "To pursue that feeling initial that you never recovered it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4914,
    "question": "traten",
    "questionDetails": "Traten de rastrear mi señal.",
    "answer": "try, treat",
    "answerDetails": "Try and home in on my signal."
  },
  {
    "id": 4915,
    "question": "conjunto",
    "questionDetails": "Tuvimos que encontrar el conjunto de los números primos positivos de menos de 100.",
    "answer": "set, whole, group",
    "answerDetails": "We had to find the set of positive prime numbers less than 100."
  },
  {
    "id": 4916,
    "question": "pasemos",
    "questionDetails": "Pero será mejor que pasemos la noche aquí.",
    "answer": "spend",
    "answerDetails": "But we better spend the night."
  },
  {
    "id": 4917,
    "question": "manden",
    "questionDetails": "Mejor antes manden una postal.",
    "answer": "send",
    "answerDetails": "Best send a postcard first."
  },
  {
    "id": 4918,
    "question": "hablaré",
    "questionDetails": "Hablaré contigo cuando termine mi reunión.",
    "answer": "i will speak, i will talk",
    "answerDetails": "I will speak with you when my meeting is over."
  },
  {
    "id": 4919,
    "question": "empiecen",
    "questionDetails": "Empiecen con los oficiales y vayan bajando en rango.",
    "answer": "start, begin",
    "answerDetails": "Start with the officers and work your way down."
  },
  {
    "id": 4920,
    "question": "encanto",
    "questionDetails": "Antes de que pudiera encender el encanto, que colgaban.",
    "answer": "charm, allure, enchantment",
    "answerDetails": "Before I could turn on the charm, they hung up."
  },
  {
    "id": 4921,
    "question": "levantó",
    "answer": "he built"
  },
  {
    "id": 4922,
    "question": "fáciles",
    "questionDetails": "Fuimos fáciles de hacer.",
    "answer": "easy, easily",
    "answerDetails": "We was easy to make."
  },
  {
    "id": 4923,
    "question": "sábanas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Puedes quitar las sábanas y ponerlas en el cesto de la ropa sucia?",
    "answer": "bedding",
    "answerDetails": "Can you strip off the bedding and put it in the laundry hamper?"
  },
  {
    "id": 4924,
    "question": "velas",
    "questionDetails": "Por una vez, velas en casa.",
    "answer": "candles, sails",
    "answerDetails": "Candles at home, for once."
  },
  {
    "id": 4925,
    "question": "productos",
    "answer": "truck"
  },
  {
    "id": 4926,
    "question": "bicho",
    "questionDetails": "Ese bicho me friquea.",
    "answer": "weirdo, critter",
    "answerDetails": "That weirdo freaks me out."
  },
  {
    "id": 4927,
    "question": "prestado",
    "questionDetails": "No peleemos por el dinero prestado. Te daré otra semana.",
    "answer": "borrowed",
    "answerDetails": "Let’s not fight over the borrowed money. I will give you another week."
  },
  {
    "id": 4928,
    "question": "mueven",
    "questionDetails": "Las señales mueven las cosas arriba y abajo.",
    "answer": "move",
    "answerDetails": "Signals move things up and down."
  },
  {
    "id": 4929,
    "question": "mudo",
    "questionDetails": "Un mudo increiblemente fuerte.",
    "answer": "mute, dumb, speechless",
    "answerDetails": "An incredibly big mute."
  },
  {
    "id": 4930,
    "question": "acceder",
    "questionDetails": "El veneno para ratas se debe colocar en un lugar donde no lo pueden acceder las mascotas.",
    "answer": "get at",
    "answerDetails": "The rat poison should be placed somewhere where pets can’t get at it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4931,
    "question": "salve",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los soldados de la legión gritaron: “¡ Salve, Emperador!”.",
    "answer": "hail",
    "answerDetails": "Every soldier of the legion cried: “Hail, Emperor!”."
  },
  {
    "id": 4932,
    "question": "infantil",
    "questionDetails": "El Partido Laborista Infantil.",
    "answer": "infant",
    "answerDetails": "The infant Labour Party."
  },
  {
    "id": 4933,
    "question": "separado",
    "questionDetails": "Su madre y su padre están separados.",
    "answer": "separate, apart",
    "answerDetails": "Her mother and father are separated."
  },
  {
    "id": 4934,
    "question": "limpiando",
    "questionDetails": "Uno de ustedes debe haber estado limpiando.",
    "answer": "cleaning, wiping, swabbing",
    "answerDetails": "One of you must have been cleaning."
  },
  {
    "id": 4935,
    "question": "escribo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo escribo un poco.",
    "answer": "write",
    "answerDetails": "I write a bit."
  },
  {
    "id": 4936,
    "question": "diciembre",
    "answer": "December"
  },
  {
    "id": 4937,
    "question": "implica",
    "answer": "it involves"
  },
  {
    "id": 4938,
    "question": "encontrarse",
    "questionDetails": "Los 2 yates zarparon y acordaron encontrarse 3 semanas más tarde en Ciudad del Cabo.",
    "answer": "rendezvous",
    "answerDetails": "The two yachts left port and arranged to rendezvous three weeks later in Cape Town."
  },
  {
    "id": 4939,
    "question": "ríe",
    "answer": "Laugh"
  },
  {
    "id": 4940,
    "question": "crecido",
    "answer": "tall"
  },
  {
    "id": 4941,
    "question": "envía",
    "questionDetails": "Le envía sus disculpas.",
    "answer": "sends, shipped, dispatches",
    "answerDetails": "He sends his apologies."
  },
  {
    "id": 4942,
    "question": "emocional",
    "questionDetails": "Él era un hombre joven fuertemente emocional.",
    "answer": "emotional",
    "answerDetails": "He was a strongly emotional young man."
  },
  {
    "id": 4943,
    "question": "impulso",
    "questionDetails": "Todos perdimos el impulso de trabajar en el proyecto después de que oímos los comentarios despreciativos de nuestro jefe.",
    "answer": "momentum, boost, impetus",
    "answerDetails": "We all lost our momentum to work on the project after we heard our boss’s disparaging remarks."
  },
  {
    "id": 4944,
    "question": "mérito",
    "questionDetails": "El cabello corto no indica ningún mérito.",
    "answer": "merit",
    "answerDetails": "Short hair is no indication of merit."
  },
  {
    "id": 4945,
    "question": "expresión",
    "answer": "utterance"
  },
  {
    "id": 4946,
    "question": "notado",
    "questionDetails": "Incluso los niños lo han notado.",
    "answer": "noticed",
    "answerDetails": "Even the kids have noticed."
  },
  {
    "id": 4947,
    "question": "tuvieran",
    "questionDetails": "Como si nuestros granos de café tuvieran pedigrí.",
    "answer": "had",
    "answerDetails": "As if every bean in our coffee had a pedigree."
  },
  {
    "id": 4948,
    "question": "jornada",
    "questionDetails": "La jornada comenzó con una presentación.",
    "answer": "day",
    "answerDetails": "The day began with an introduction."
  },
  {
    "id": 4949,
    "question": "hijita",
    "questionDetails": "Y ahora, mi hijita está enferma.",
    "answer": "little girl",
    "answerDetails": "And now my little girl is sick."
  },
  {
    "id": 4950,
    "question": "andá",
    "questionDetails": "Andá a dormir entonces.",
    "answer": "go",
    "answerDetails": "Go to sleep then."
  },
  {
    "id": 4951,
    "question": "fiscalía",
    "questionDetails": "La fiscalía tiene todavía un testigo.",
    "answer": "prosecution, procuracy, prosecutorial",
    "answerDetails": "Prosecution has another witness."
  },
  {
    "id": 4952,
    "question": "suélteme",
    "answer": "let me go"
  },
  {
    "id": 4953,
    "question": "nene",
    "questionDetails": "Lo hago todo por ti, nene.",
    "answer": "baby",
    "answerDetails": "I do everything for you, baby."
  },
  {
    "id": 4954,
    "question": "óyeme",
    "questionDetails": "Óyeme podríamos llevar a este …",
    "answer": "listen",
    "answerDetails": "Listen we could get this …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4955,
    "question": "you",
    "questionDetails": "I’ll Order After you.",
    "answer": "ti, os",
    "answerDetails": "Yo pediré después de ti."
  },
  {
    "id": 4956,
    "question": "sincera",
    "questionDetails": "Se que eres sincera y bien intencionada.",
    "answer": "sincere, honest, heartfelt",
    "answerDetails": "You that you are sincere and very deliberate."
  },
  {
    "id": 4957,
    "question": "regresamos",
    "questionDetails": "Después del concierto, regresamos a mi casa.",
    "answer": "we returned",
    "answerDetails": "After the concert, we returned to my house."
  },
  {
    "id": 4958,
    "question": "tragos",
    "questionDetails": "Me detuve en el camino por un par de tragos.",
    "answer": "drinks, swigs, gulps",
    "answerDetails": "I stopped along the way for a couple of drinks."
  },
  {
    "id": 4959,
    "question": "liberar",
    "questionDetails": "El rey ha proclamado que liberará a todos los prisioneros de guerra.",
    "answer": "release, liberate, unlock",
    "answerDetails": "The King has proclaimed that he will release all prisoners of war."
  },
  {
    "id": 4960,
    "question": "vuestro",
    "questionDetails": "Este es vuestro momento.",
    "answer": "your",
    "answerDetails": "This is your moment."
  },
  {
    "id": 4961,
    "question": "celulares",
    "questionDetails": "Extraen nuestros péptidos celulares.",
    "answer": "cellular, cell, phones",
    "answerDetails": "They extract our cellular peptides."
  },
  {
    "id": 4962,
    "question": "ordenó",
    "questionDetails": "Le ordenó al mesero a limpiar la mesa.",
    "answer": "he told",
    "answerDetails": "He told the waiter to clean up the table."
  },
  {
    "id": 4963,
    "question": "seguís",
    "questionDetails": "O me lleváis con vosotros o me seguís allí.",
    "answer": "follow",
    "answerDetails": "Either take me with you or follow me there."
  },
  {
    "id": 4964,
    "question": "investigaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Hay que llevar a cabo más investigaciones sobre la influencia de los medios sociales en nuestras vidas.",
    "answer": "research",
    "answerDetails": "We need to carry out more research on the influence of social media on our lives."
  },
  {
    "id": 4965,
    "question": "cometí",
    "questionDetails": "Quizás cometí un error con las columnas.",
    "answer": "made",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe made a mistake with the columns."
  },
  {
    "id": 4966,
    "question": "acusando",
    "questionDetails": "No estamos acusando a nadie.",
    "answer": "accusing",
    "answerDetails": "We are not accusing anyone."
  },
  {
    "id": 4967,
    "question": "horribles",
    "questionDetails": "Me sigo acordando de cosas buenas en lugar de horribles.",
    "answer": "horrible, awful, hideous",
    "answerDetails": "I keep thinking of nice things instead of horrible ones."
  },
  {
    "id": 4968,
    "question": "encargue",
    "questionDetails": "Deja que alguien más se encargue.",
    "answer": "handle",
    "answerDetails": "Let someone else handle it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4969,
    "question": "agarran",
    "questionDetails": "pero ellos agarran a la presa y comienzan a hacerla girar …",
    "answer": "seize",
    "answerDetails": "but they seize it and start spinning …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4970,
    "question": "lastimar",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca lastimaría a un hombre indefenso.",
    "answer": "harm",
    "answerDetails": "I would never harm an unarmed man."
  },
  {
    "id": 4971,
    "question": "meterle",
    "questionDetails": "Meterle ese radio por la cabeza.",
    "answer": "shove, put",
    "answerDetails": "Shove that radio right through the side of his head."
  },
  {
    "id": 4972,
    "question": "borracha",
    "questionDetails": "Yo estaba muy borracha.",
    "answer": "drunk, drunken, lush",
    "answerDetails": "I was so drunk."
  },
  {
    "id": 4973,
    "question": "imbéciles",
    "questionDetails": "Imbéciles morales ante el hombre común.",
    "answer": "imbeciles, jerks, idiots",
    "answerDetails": "Moral imbeciles to a man."
  },
  {
    "id": 4974,
    "question": "beneficios",
    "questionDetails": "La empresa cuestiona si podrá sostener el crecimiento de beneficios con 1$ más fuerte.",
    "answer": "earnings, gains",
    "answerDetails": "The company questions whether it will be able to retain its earnings growth with a stronger dollar."
  },
  {
    "id": 4975,
    "question": "impuestos",
    "questionDetails": "Los impuestos son un hecho.",
    "answer": "taxes, taxation, imposed",
    "answerDetails": "Taxes are a fact."
  },
  {
    "id": 4976,
    "question": "cuenten",
    "questionDetails": "Y ciertamente cuenten con mi apoyo.",
    "answer": "count",
    "answerDetails": "And indeed count on my support."
  },
  {
    "id": 4977,
    "question": "patrulla",
    "questionDetails": "Romper a los cachorros en seises y Scouts en patrullas.",
    "answer": "patrol",
    "answerDetails": "Break the Cubs into sixes and Scouts into patrols."
  },
  {
    "id": 4978,
    "question": "defenderme",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo derecho a defenderme.",
    "answer": "defend myself",
    "answerDetails": "I have a right to defend myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 4979,
    "question": "torta",
    "questionDetails": "Usted no ha recibido una porción justa de la torta de la educación.",
    "answer": "cake",
    "answerDetails": "You have not received a fair slice of the education cake."
  },
  {
    "id": 4980,
    "question": "legales",
    "questionDetails": "Los derechos legales de la investigación son claros.",
    "answer": "legal, statutory, lawful",
    "answerDetails": "The legal investigation rights are clear."
  },
  {
    "id": 4981,
    "question": "arregle",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que arregle relojes también.",
    "answer": "fix, straightened out",
    "answerDetails": "He might fix clocks, too."
  },
  {
    "id": 4982,
    "question": "confesión",
    "questionDetails": "La confesión del ladrón finalmente puso fin a la investigación.",
    "answer": "admission, confession",
    "answerDetails": "The thief’s admission finally brought the investigation to a close."
  },
  {
    "id": 4983,
    "question": "lotería",
    "questionDetails": "Se sacó la lotería.",
    "answer": "jackpot",
    "answerDetails": "She really hit the jackpot."
  },
  {
    "id": 4984,
    "question": "regala",
    "questionDetails": "Así que regala los dólares.",
    "answer": "gives",
    "answerDetails": "So it gives the dollars away."
  },
  {
    "id": 4985,
    "question": "vivas",
    "questionDetails": "Me preocupa tanto que vivas sola.",
    "answer": "living, alive, vivid",
    "answerDetails": "I worry so about you living alone."
  },
  {
    "id": 4986,
    "question": "relajado",
    "questionDetails": "Hace dos segundos estaba relajado.",
    "answer": "relaxed",
    "answerDetails": "I was relaxed about two seconds ago."
  },
  {
    "id": 4987,
    "question": "prometer",
    "questionDetails": "Ella me hizo prometer no decírselo a nadie.",
    "answer": "promise",
    "answerDetails": "She made me promise not to tell a soul."
  },
  {
    "id": 4988,
    "question": "psicólogo",
    "questionDetails": "Éste es el número de mi psicólogo.",
    "answer": "psychologist",
    "answerDetails": "This is the number of my psychologist."
  },
  {
    "id": 4989,
    "question": "alcanzó",
    "answer": "Reached"
  },
  {
    "id": 4990,
    "question": "agarrado",
    "questionDetails": "Ruy se corta el pelo él mismo y se niega a ir a un barbero porque es agarrado.",
    "answer": "tightfisted",
    "answerDetails": "Ruy cuts his own hair and refuses to see a barber because he is tightfisted."
  },
  {
    "id": 4991,
    "question": "espiando",
    "questionDetails": "Alguien estuvo espiando el juego de cartas.",
    "answer": "spying on, spying, peeping",
    "answerDetails": "Someone was spying on the card game."
  },
  {
    "id": 4992,
    "question": "tomarnos",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que todos deberíamos tomarnos un descanso ahora.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "I think maybe everyone should take a break now."
  },
  {
    "id": 4993,
    "question": "cambias",
    "questionDetails": "Pero si lo único que cambias es la fecha.",
    "answer": "change",
    "answerDetails": "All you do is change the date."
  },
  {
    "id": 4994,
    "question": "interesan",
    "questionDetails": "Ni siquiera me interesan más las mujeres.",
    "answer": "interest, interested",
    "answerDetails": "Even women don’t interest me any more."
  },
  {
    "id": 4995,
    "question": "intensa",
    "questionDetails": "En un solo lugar, pero muy intensa.",
    "answer": "intense, intensely",
    "answerDetails": "It is localized, but very intense."
  },
  {
    "id": 4996,
    "question": "cambies",
    "questionDetails": "Sugiero que te cambies por algo más apropiado.",
    "answer": "change",
    "answerDetails": "I suggest you change into something more suitable."
  },
  {
    "id": 4997,
    "question": "tomate",
    "questionDetails": "Estos tomates se ven deliciosos.",
    "answer": "tomato",
    "answerDetails": "These tomatoes look delicious."
  },
  {
    "id": 4998,
    "question": "entiendan",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que esos convictos entiendan quién manda.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "I want those cons to understand who owns them."
  },
  {
    "id": 4999,
    "question": "cruel",
    "questionDetails": "Que era cruel de ella para criticar.",
    "answer": "unkind, callous",
    "answerDetails": "It was unkind of her to criticize."
  },
  {
    "id": 5000,
    "question": "abandonada",
    "questionDetails": "Una aldea abandonada, sin habitantes.",
    "answer": "abandoned, deserted, derelict",
    "answerDetails": "An abandoned village, a ghost town."
  }
]